

Profile

Graduated in Electrical Engineering, I was a co-founder of the Fenrir Team, an extension project focused on energy efficiency. I also participated in an exchange program at Hakuoh University, Japan, where I studied the Japanese language and gained intercultural and intersocial experience.

I began my professional career as a Systems Analyst focused on SCADA systems, and I am currently working as a Full Stack Developer specializing in React, Nest, Golang, and AWS.

Employment History

Full Stack Developer, 4all - Hub de Tecnologia, São Paulo

JANUARY 2023 - PRESENT

- Performance as a Full Stack Developer, working as part of an agile development team focused on enhancing the user's online shopping experience (food, tickets, e-shop, etc.) through a digital marketplace.
- Main clients I have interacted with: major spanish football clubs, including Atlético de Madrid and Espanyol de Barcelona.
- I work on developing new features and maintaining the digital product.
 Constantly handle integrations with external services and payment gateways, as well as contribute to building the entire architecture.

Novice Full Stack Developer, Agência Molla, São Paulo

SEPTEMBER 2022 - NOVEMBER 2022

- Worked as a Full Stack TypeScript software developer, building applications focused on Trade Marketing portals and advertising incentive campaigns.
- Developed the **Front-End** using **React**, with Hooks, Context API, and Tailwind, as well as **Axios** for API consumption.
- Built the **Back-End** with **NestJS**, developing RESTful JSON APIs and integrating with a **PostgreSQL** database using **TypeORM**.
- Utilized **Docker** to create containers and fully containerize the application using **docker-compose** and **Dockerfile**.
- Used Swagger for API documentation.

ICC Application Analyst, Alstom, São Paulo

SEPTEMBER 2021 - SEPTEMBER 2022

- Worked as a system integrator and configurator in IT, utilizing Alstom's product softwares, from architecture to data acquisition and supervision, in the railway signaling sector for projects such as ROCA Line (Buenos Aires), Line 2 of Santiago (Chile), and São Paulo Metro.
- Developed **user interfaces** for the control, supervision, and operation of metro-rail transportation for end customers.
- Extensive use of **SQL**, **C#**, **Batch Script**, **and VB** for database manipulation and configuration in **SQL Server**, as well as process automation.
- Familiar with DevOps culture and Git.

Details

São Paulo

Brasil

(11) 96418-3246

yuji.soyama@gmail.com

Links

LinkedIn

Github

Web Portifolio

Skills

React

Nest

Golang

Microsserviços

gRPC

API REST

Postgres

Typescript

Tailwind CSS

Amazon Web Services

Vite

Docker

VBA

SQL Server

Languages

English

Japanese

Portuguese

System Analyst, Siemens, São Paulo

DECEMBER 2020 - AUGUST 2021

- Worked on **field commissioning activities** for electrical panels and automation systems in **railway power supply substations** for **CPTM Lines 9, 10, and 11**.
- Responsible for developing monitoring, supervision, control, and data acquisition (SCADA) software for the implemented systems.
- Interacted with client requirements regarding SCADA user interface systems and conducted training sessions for end-user operators to ensure proper system operation at CPTM's control center.

Automation and Digitalization Internship, Siemens, São Paulo

JANUARY 2020 - DECEMBER 2020

- Assisted in the development of electrical panels and auxiliary systems
 responsible for the automation and protection of substations and cabins for
 railway systems in the CPTM Line 9, 10, and 11 projects.
- Prepared and reviewed **projects and documentation** using **AutoCAD**.
- Developed a VBA-based tool to create an interface between Excel and AutoCAD, optimizing and automating internal processes.

Eletronic and Data Team Member, Equipe Fenrir, Guaratinguetá

NOVEMBER 2016 - DECEMBER 2020

- As one of the co-founders of the project and a member of the Electronics and Data subteam, I was responsible for researching and testing solutions for electric motor drives in an automotive prototype for the Shell Eco-Marathon competition.
- Worked as a Full Stack Developer, using React and Node.js to build an
 application for speed monitoring and time control of the automotive prototype.

Education

Bachelor in Electrical Engineering, UNESP - Universidade Estadual Paulista, Guaratinguetá - SP

2015 - 2020

Exchange Program, Hakuoh University, Oyama - Tochigi

2018 - 2019